A Guide to the Social Science Research Council records, Near & Middle East, Record Group 3, Series 9 FA1777
Rockefeller Archive Center
Social Science Research Council records, Near & Middle East, Record Group 3, Series 9
1968-1996
Rockefeller Archive Center
Social Science Research Council
FA1777
30.33 Cubic Feet 77 boxes (62 letter document boxes, 14 legal document boxes, 1 half letter document box)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
The Social Science Research Council records, Near and Middle East, Record Group 3, Series 9 contains program materials related to committee meetings, administrative tasks, conferences, workshops, publications, research papers, awards, fellowships, and grants of the Joint Committee for Near and Middle East and the Joint Committee for the Comparative Study of Muslim Societies.
Arrangement
The Social Science Research Council archives are arranged into three record groups distinguished by the date of their donation to the Archive Center. Accession 1 (Record Group 1) consists of the documents received by the Archive Center in 1990; Accession 2 (Record Group 2) was transferred to the Archive Center in 1994; Record Group 3 was transferred to the Archive Center in 2017-2018. Within series the records are primarily arranged in original order. Within Near and Middle East, Record Group 3, Series 9, there are two subseries: 1.) Joint Committee on the Near and Middle East, 1968-1996 and 2.) Joint Committee on the Comparative Study of Muslim Societies, 1984-1995.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records in this series were received from the Social Science Research Council from 2017-2018.
Near East studies; Middle East studies
- Joint Committee on the Near and Middle East, 1959-1996; 1; 26.06 Cubic Feet 66 containers
  Biographical / Historical
  In 1951, the Social Science Research Council established a committee to promote understanding of the contemporary Near and Middle East by developing social science materials and trained personnel in the field. In 1959, the Committee was reorganized as a joint committee of the Social Science Research Council and the American Council of Learned Societies. The Joint Committee on the Near and Middle East oversaw the Ibn Khaldun prize graduate student writing competition (beginning in 1984), led dissertation workshops, bestowed advanced research grants, organized conferences, produced publications, and awarded 38 dissertation fellowships over its lifetime. In 1996, the Social Science Research Council restructured its region-focused committees in response to changing scholarship priorities in the field of area studies. Funding for the committee's activities came from the Ford Foundation, the National Endowment for the Humanities, the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, and the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation. The Social Science Research Council itself is not a foundation, although it possesses a small sustaining fund. It does not depend on an endowment for its income, as do foundations; rather, it is a claimant agency to foundations for grants which have terms of one to five years.
  Scope and Contents
  The Joint Committee on the Near and Middle East subseries contains committee meeting minutes and agendas, reviewed applications for advanced research grants for postdoctoral studies, reviewed applications for dissertation fellowships for predoctoral candidates, papers submitted to the Ibn Khaldun prize graduate student writing competition, correspondence related to the Near and Middle East Research Training Act (NMERTA), committee financial reports, grant proposals for committee funding, papers for conferences and committee publications, regional seminar materials, administrative correspondence, workshop materials, subcommittee and task force documents, and invitations to the Subcommittee on Law and Social Structure Summer Institute.
  - Meeting Minutes and Agenda, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Research Fellowships and Grants, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
  - Copies of Near and Middle East Annual Activities Publication, 1959-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize - Student Transcripts (Box 77, Folder 783)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted - student records
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize Mailing Lists, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize Papers, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11-13)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Near and Middle East Research Training Act (NMERTA) - Application Materials, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
  - Near and Middle East Research Training Act (NMERTA) - General Application Information, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
  - Near and Middle East Research Training Act (NMERTA) - Appendices, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Near and Middle East Research Training Act (NMERTA), 1992 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Fall 1994 Meeting Agenda Materials, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 21-24)
  - Potential New Members, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Copy of Near and Middle East Research and Training Act (NMERTA), State Department Authorization Bill, Fiscal Year 1992 and 1993 and Letters of Support, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Title VIII, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Near and Middle East Research Training Act (NMERTA) - Middle East Studies Association (MESA) Materials, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 28, Box 4, Folder 29-30)
  - Social Science Research Council Proposal - Ottoman Legacies: Sultanistic Politics and Sectarian Societies in Eastern Europe and the Middle East, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Political Economy Workshop Submissions, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Predoctoral Research Reports, 1983-1988 (Box 4, Folder 33-37)
  - Postdoctoral Research Reports, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 38-39)
  - State and Society Papers, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
    Israel's Myth of Pioneering and the Elusive Distinction Between Society and State, Uri Ben-Eliezer
    Law, Property, and State Power in the Ottoman Empire, Huri Islamoglu-Inan
  - Title VIII Funds - Near and Middle East Research Training Act (NMERTA) Background, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Remapping the Middle East - Spring 1993 Agenda (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Political Economy Workshop, Berkeley, California, February 10-13, 1994, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 43-46)
  - Near and Middle East Research Training Act (NMERTA) - Proposal for Predoctoral Fellowship Program Agreement, 1993-1995 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize Papers, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Task Force on Stratification in the Middle East - Papers and Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Food and Agriculture in the Middle East - Westview Press, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Food Crisis and State Policy in the Near and Middle East, Alan Richards, 1982-1984 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Task Force on Stratification in the Middle East - Meeting, 1983 March 19 (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - Task Force on Stratification in the Middle East - Planning, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - Task Force on Stratification in the Middle East - Discharge, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize Papers, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Position Papers, 1985 March (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - Financial Status and Reports, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - Committee Members, 1982-1983; 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 76-77)
  - Committee Appointments, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 78-79)
  - Task Force on Social Change in Arab Oil-Producing Countries - Discharge, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - Polity, Economy, and Society in 19th and Early 20th Century Turkey and Maghreb, edited by Peter von Sivers - Transfer of Rights Documents, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 81)
  - Polity, Economy, and Society in 19th and Early 20th Century Turkey and Maghreb, edited by Peter von Sivers - Correspondence, 1975-1984 (Box 11, Folder 82)
  - Cultural Change in the Mediterranean World and the Near East in Late Antiquity, Regional Seminar, University of Wisconsin, R. Stephen Humphreys, 1982-1984 (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - Midwest Middle East Consortium, Notre Dame, Evelyn Early, 1981-1983 (Box 11, Folder 84)
  - Islam, Political Development, and the State, Leonard Binder, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - Returning Unused Funds for Middle East Regional Seminars, Joseph Szyliocwicz, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - Alternative Middle East Studies Seminar (AMESS), Dynamics of Social Transformation in the Middle East, University of Texas at Austin, Kristin Koptiuch, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 87)
  - Defense Intelligence Agency, Defense Academic Research Support Program - Requests for Proposals, 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 88)
  - Joint Committee on the Near and Middle East Editorial Subcommittee, 1981-1983 (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee Warning on America-Israel Public Affairs Committee Questionnaire, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - Committee Meeting, Morocco, 1984 August (Box 11, Folder 91)
  - Committee Meeting, New York City, 1984 February (Box 11, Folder 92)
  - Conference Proposals, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - Committee Meeting Preliminary Agenda, 1982 February (Box 11, Folder 94)
  - Papers for Fall 1985 Meeting (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - Planning for Committee Meeting, Berlin, 1985 October (Box 12, Folder 96)
  - State-of-the-Field - Reflection and Position Paper, 1980-1985 (Box 12, Folder 97)
  - Middle East Studies Association - Mailing List, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 98)
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize Papers, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 99)
  - Agenda Document for August 1984 Meeting (Box 12, Folder 100)
  - Task Force on Stratification in the Middle East - Minutes, 1981 November 20-21 (Box 12, Folder 101)
  - Islam, Ethnicity, and the State in Afghanistan, Iran, and Pakistan - Conference Arrangements, November 11-13, 1982, 1982-1984 (Box 12, Folder 102)
  - Task Force on Stratification in the Middle East - Meeting October 30-31, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 103)
  - Task Force on Stratification in the Middle East: Meeting, 1982 April 24-25 (Box 13, Folder 104)
  - Committee Expense Statements, 1985-1987 (Box 13, Folder 105-106)
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize Papers, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 107-108)
  - State Formation and Nation Building in Arab Oil-Producing Societies - Proposal Documents and Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 109)
  - Macmillan Correspondence (Arjomand volume), 1983-1985 (Box 14, Folder 110)
  - From Nationalism to Revolutionary Islam - Transfer of Rights Forms, 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 111)
  - Task Force on Social Change in Arab Oil Producing Countries, 1981-1983 (Box 14, Folder 112)
  - Oil Project - Ford Grant (Job #32), 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 113)
  - Project on Oil and Social Change - State Formation and Nation-Building in Arab Oil-Producing Countries - Planning, 1983-1985 (Box 14, Folder 114-115)
  - Request for Funding for a Conference on the Food Problem and State Policy in the Middle East, Alan Richards, 1984 January (Box 14, Folder 116)
  - Proposal for the Creation of a Research Seminar on Oil Wealth and State Formation in the Oil-Producing Countries of the Arab World, Latin America and West Africa, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 117)
  - Editorial Work (Arjomand Volume - From Nationalism to Revolutionary Islam), 1981-1984 (Box 14, Folder 118)
  - Symposium Papers, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 119)
  - Ghassan Salam Papers, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 120)
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize Papers, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 121)
  - Proposals, Clippings, Articles, and Conference Planning Materials, 1982-1991 (Box 19, Folder 152-154, Box 20, Folder 155)
  - Articles, 1974-1988 (Box 18, Folder 149-150, Box 19, Folder 151)
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize Papers, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 156-158, Box 21, Folder 159-161)
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize - Student Transcripts, 1993 (Box 77, Folder 784)
    Restricted - Student records
  - Steve Heydemann Social Science Research Council Correspondence - Files Word55, circa 1990s; 3.5" floppy disk (Box 21)
    Open for research. Digital access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - Steve Heydemann Social Science Research Council Correspondence - LTR, 1991-1994; 3.5" floppy disk (Box 21)
  - Steve Heydemann Social Science Research Council Correspondence - LTR, 1995-1997; 3.5" floppy disk (Box 21)
  - Questions of Modernity: Bridging Scholarship on the Middle East and South Asia, National Endowment for the Humanities Conference Proposal Submitted by the Social Science Research Council, 1996 (Box 21, Folder 162)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities Conference Proposal - Questions of Modernity: Bridging Scholarship on the Middle East and South Asia, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 163)
  - Retreating States and Expanding Societies: The State Autonomy/Informal Civil Society Dialectic in the Middle East and North Africa, Peter von Sivers, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 164)
  - Committee Spring 1992 Meeting (Box 21, Folder 165)
  - Committee Correspondence, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 166)
  - Committee Meeting Agenda, 1992 September (Box 22, Folder 167)
  - Committee Fall 1992 Meeting - Istanbul (Box 22, Folder 168)
  - Committee Spring 1994 Meeting - Agenda Materials, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 169)
  - Committee Spring 1994 Meeting Information, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 170)
  - Committee Fall 1993 Meeting Information (Box 22, Folder 171)
  - Fall 1993 Agenda Materials, Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina (Box 22, Folder 172)
  - United States Institute of Peace and the Ford Foundation - War, the State, and Society in the Middle East - Proposal and Drafts, undated (Box 22, Folder 173)
  - United States Institute of Peace Grant Application Forms, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 174)
  - Bellagio Conference Application - War as a Source of State and Social Transformation in the Middle East, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 175)
  - The State, Society, and the War in the Middle East - Invitations and Responses, 1991-1992 (Box 23, Folder 176-177)
  - Committee Meeting, Morocco, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 178)
  - War, the State, and Society in the Middle East - Memos and Correspondence, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 179)
  - War, the State, and Society in the Middle East, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 180)
  - War, the State, and Society in the Middle East - Book, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 181)
  - War, the State, and Society in the Middle East - Proposal, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 182)
  - Ford Foundation Grant - War, the State, and Society in the Middle East, 1990-1992 (Box 23, Folder 183)
  - United States Institute of Peace - War, the State, and Society in the Middle East, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 184)
  - Questions of Modernity, Tim Mitchell and Lila Abu-Lughod, 1989-1993 (Box 23, Folder 185-186)
  - Questions of Modernity Conference, 1991-1993 (Box 23, Folder 187)
  - Questions of Modernity Conference - Revised Papers, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 188)
  - Questions of Modernity Conference - Papers, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 189-191)
  - Papers Presented at Conferences, 1989-1990 (Box 24, Folder 192)
  - Questions of Modernity Conference - Papers, 1993-1994 (Box 25, Folder 193-197, Box 26, Folder 198)
  - Economic Liberalization, Illiberal Politics, Kiren Chaudhry, 1991-1993 (Box 26, Folder 199)
  - Comparative and Transnational Research Project Proposals, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 200)
  - War as a Source of State and Social Transformation in the Middle East, Comparative and Transnational Research Grant Competition, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 201)
  - Comparative and Transnational Research Project Proposals, 1990-1992 (Box 26, Folder 202-204)
  - Memos, 1994-1995 (Box 26, Folder 205)
  - Membership Memos, 1993-1995 (Box 26, Folder 206)
  - Fellowships, 1982-1990 (Box 26, Folder 207-211, Box 27, Folder 212)
  - Memos to Finance, 1991-1992 (Box 27, Folder 213)
  - State Creation and Transformation Workshop, Istanbul - Papers, 1989-1990 (Box 27, Folder 214)
  - State-Society Workshop, Seattle, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 215)
  - Fall 1991 Meeting Expenses (Box 27, Folder 216)
  - Fall 1990 Workshop, Oxford (Box 27, Folder 217)
  - Committee Memos, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 218)
  - Committee Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 27, Folder 219)
  - Committee Budgets, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 220)
  - General Finances, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 221)
  - Steven Heydeman's Form Letter to Middle East Scholars and Responses, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 222)
  - Letter to Middle Eastern Scholars, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 223)
  - Readings on Migration, 1985-1992 (Box 28, Folder 224)
  - Near and Middle East Grants for Advanced Research - Evaluation Form and Procedures, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 225)
  - Note Sheets for Near and Middle East Fellowship Screenings, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 226)
  - State and Society in the Middle East Volume - Revisions, 1990-1992 (Box 28, Folder 227-228)
  - Meeting Minutes, New York, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 229)
  - Agenda for Spring 1988 Meeting (Box 28, Folder 230)
  - Spring Meeting, Hanover, New Hampshire, 1990 March 23 (Box 29, Folder 231)
  - Notes on Fall 1989 Workshop - State and Society in the Middle East (Box 29, Folder 232)
  - Recent Fellow Publications, 1988-1989 (Box 29, Folder 233)
  - State Formation, Historical Memory, and Popular Culture in Arab Oil-Producing Countries, Eric Davis, 1988-1990 (Box 29, Folder 234)
  - Committee Meeting, 1990 March (Box 29, Folder 235)
  - Conferences - Requests for Funds, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 236)
  - Committee Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 29, Folder 237)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities Requested Information, 1987-1990 (Box 29, Folder 238)
  - Committee Meeting Minutes, 1981-1988 (Box 29, Folder 239-240)
  - Committee Meeting Finances, 1990-1991 (Box 29, Folder 241)
  - Past Meeting Minutes, 1985-1987 (Box 29, Folder 242)
  - Meeting Spring 1991, 1990-1991 (Box 29, Folder 243)
  - Fall Meeting Agenda, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 244)
  - Committee Meeting, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 245)
  - Tablighi Jama'at Workshop Papers, 1988-1990 (Box 31, Folder 274)
  - Committee Chron Files, 1990-1992 (Box 31, Folder 275, Box 32, Folder 276-277)
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize Papers, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 278, Box 33, Folder 279-281)
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize - Student Transcripts, 1995 (Box 77, Folder 785)
  - Dissertation Workshop Applications, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 282-283, Box 34, Folder 284-285, Box 35, Folder 286)
  - Bridging the Divide: Comparing North/South Models of State and Society Workshop, Lyon, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 287)
  - Figuring the Family: Comparative Perspectives on the Family in the Post-WWII Middle East Proposal, 1991-1994 (Box 35, Folder 288-289)
  - Law and Property as Aspects of State Power in Historical Development of Capitalist Market Relations and Industrialisation Workshop, 1991-1992 (Box 35, Folder 290-291)
  - Hegland, Mary - Near and Middle Research Grant 1985, 1985-1987 (Box 35, Folder 292)
  - Henry, Clement - Near and Middle East Advanced Research Grant 1988 - Postdoctoral Award, 1987-1988 (Box 35, Folder 293)
  - Messier, Ronald - Near and Middle East Advanced Research Grant 1988 - Postdoctoral Award, 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 294)
  - Miller, Susan - Near and Middle East Advanced International Research Grant - Postdoctoral Award, 1987-1989 (Box 36, Folder 295)
  - Schuyler, Philip - Near and Middle East Advanced Research Grant 1988 - Postdoctoral Award, 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 296)
  - Sheikholeslami, Ali Reza - Near and Middle East Advanced Research Grant 1988 - Postdoctoral Award, 1987-1989 (Box 36, Folder 297)
  - Zartman, I. William - Near and Middle East Advanced Research Grant 1988 - Postdoctoral Award, 1987-1990 (Box 36, Folder 298)
  - Hegland, Mary - Near and Middle East Advanced Research Grant 1988 - Postdoctoral Award, 1984-1993 (Box 36, Folder 299)
  - Whitaker, Meri - Near and Middle East International Doctoral Research 1988 Fellowship - Predoctoral Award, 1987-1989 (Box 36, Folder 300)
  - Anderson, Lisa Scott - Near and Middle East Advanced Research Grant 1988 - Postdoctoral Award, 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 301)
  - Ansari, Hamied N. - Near and Middle East Advanced Research Grant 1988 - Postdoctoral Award, 1987-1990 (Box 36, Folder 302)
  - Chaudry, Kiren Aziz - Near and Middle East Advanced Research Grant 1988 - Postdoctoral Award, 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 303)
  - Fattah, Hala - Near and Middle East Advanced Research Grant 1988 - Postdoctoral Award, 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 304)
  - Gran, Peter - Near and Middle East Advanced Research Grant 1988 - Postdoctoral Award, 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 305)
  - Mitchell, Edward Black - Near and Middle East Dissertation Fellowship 1988 - Predoctoral Award, 1987-1989 (Box 37, Folder 306)
  - Hammami, Rema - Near and Middle East Dissertation Fellowship 1988 - Predoctoral Award, 1987-1989 (Box 37, Folder 307)
  - Al-Qattan, Najwa - Near and Middle East Dissertation Fellowship 1988 - Predoctoral Award, 1988-1990 (Box 37, Folder 308)
  - Soos, Regina - Near and Middle East Dissertation Fellowship 1988 - Predoctoral Award, 1987-1990 (Box 37, Folder 309)
  - Retreating States and Expanding Societies: The State Autonomy - Informal Civil Society Dialectic in the Middle East and North Africa - Original Conference Documents, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 310)
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize Papers, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 311)
  - Ibn Khaldun Prize - Transcripts, 1995 (Box 77, Folder 786)
  - World Chaos and the "Imaginary:" A Quest on the World's Fringes, Evelyne Accad and Paul Vielle - Proposal, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 312)
  - Potential Mellon Funding, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 313)
  - Non-Near and Middle East - State Creation and Transformation Papers, 1988-1989 (Box 38, Folder 314)
  - State Creation and Transformation, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 315)
  - Vocabularies of the State - Papers, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 316)
  - Retreating States and Expanding Societies: The State Autononomy/Informal Civil Society Dialectic in the Middle East and North Africa Conference, 1987-1988 (Box 38, Folder 317)
  - McMurray, David Andrew - Near and Middle East International Doctoral Research 1985 Fellowship - Predoctoral, 1984-1988 (Box 38, Folder 318)
  - Messina, Maria - Near and Middle East International Doctoral Research 1985 Fellowship - Predoctoral, 1984-1985 (Box 38, Folder 319)
  - Chaudry, Kiren - Near and Middle East International Doctoral Research 1985 Fellowship - Predoctoral, 1985-1986 (Box 38, Folder 320)
  - Singerman, Diane - Near and Middle East International Doctoral Research 1985 Fellowship - Predoctoral, 1984-1985 (Box 38, Folder 321)
  - Macmillan, Ewen G. (Saudi Arabia) - Near and Middle East International Doctoral Research 1982 Fellowship - Predoctoral, 1983-1985 (Box 38, Folder 322)
  - Koptituch, Kristin - Near and Middle East International Doctoral Research 1979 Fellowship - Predoctoral, 1979-1981 (Box 38, Folder 323)
  - Bolak, Hale - Near and Middle East International Doctoral Research 1986 Fellowship - Predoctoral, 1985-1987 (Box 39, Folder 324)
  - Constable, Olivia - Near and Middle East International Doctoral Research 1987 Fellowship - Predoctoral, 1985-1987 (Box 39, Folder 325)
  - Doumani, Beshara - Near and Middle East International Doctoral Research 1986 Fellowship - Predoctoral, 1986-1988 (Box 39, Folder 326)
  - Glazer, Steven - Near and Middle East International Doctoral Research 1986 Fellowship - Predoctoral, 1986-1988 (Box 39, Folder 327)
  - Reimer, Michael - Near and Middle East International Doctoral Research 1986 Fellowship - Predoctoral, 1985-1988 (Box 39, Folder 328)
  - Abu-Lughod, Janet - Near and Middle East Advanced Research Grant 1986 - Postdoctoral, 1985-1986 (Box 39, Folder 329)
  - Cinar, E. Mine - Near and Middle East Advanced Research Grant 1986 - Postdoctoral, 1985-1986 (Box 39, Folder 330)